From January to October 2023, the average full cost of aluminum in China was around 16,536 yuan/mt, down 8.1% YoY. The average profit was about 2,110 yuan/mt, up 9% YoY.
From January to October 2023, the average full cost of aluminum in China was around 16,536 yuan/mt, down 8.1% YoY. The average profit was about 2,110 yuan/mt, up 9% YoY.

In September 2023, with domestic alumina prices rebounding, stable power costs, and a slight increase in coal prices for some captive power plants, the full cost of aluminum saw a 0.51% monthly increase to 15,640 yuan/mt.

In the same month, the average spot price of aluminum was around 19,538 yuan/mt. The average industry profit was about 3,898 yuan/mt, up 26% MoM, and 268% YoY.